[MUSIC PLAYING]
Matt  我正在为感到孤独的人打造一个网络应用
ADDY OSMANI: So Matt, I'm working on a new web app for lonely people.
不错
MATT GAUNT: OK.
它是干什么的
What does it do?
它叫什么
What is it called?
叫做  跟猫聊天
ADDY OSMANI: It's called "Words With Cats." Now-- Words With Cats.
这名字很好
It's a brilliant name.
我希望手机主屏幕上能有个图标
Now, I want to show an icon on my phone's home screen,
如果有人启动它
if someone launches this, and I also
我希望能像一个图标一样
want to be able to show like an icon or some visual
或者有启动画面
in a splash screen.
比如一只猫在翻字典之类的
MATT GAUNT: Of a cat reading a dictionary, or something?
一只猫读  你真是智多星
ADDY OSMANI: A cat reading-- you're 're a thought leader.
我怎么才能做到
How can I get that done?
Chrome 现在有添加到主屏幕功能
MATT GAUNT: So Chrome now has the add to home screen stuff.
基本上  你只要满足一些条件
So, basically, if you meet a certain set of criteria
当用户使用你的网络应用时
when a user is basically engaged in your web app,
会有一条小横幅
it will come a little banner saying, hey, would to add this
上面写着是否把它添加到主屏幕
to your home screen.
你需要使用 HTTPS
So, you basically need to be on HBS,
service worker  以及 web app manifest
and to have a service worker, and you need a web app manifest.
之后的话
And then after that it's basically,
只要用户多次使用了
depending on the user coming back a couple of times,
就会出现横幅提示
then it will show the banner.
你所需要的主要是 web app manifest
So the web app manifest is the main thing
它能实现这些功能  当然还有其他的
that you need, to enable all of this, along with the other bits.
但是 manifest 现在只是一个 JSON 文件
But the manifest is just a JSON file at that point.
棒
ADDY OSMANI: Cool.
它只是一个 JSON 文件
So it's just a JSON file.
仅限于 Chrome 平台么
Is this a Chrome-only thing?
不
MATT GAUNT: No, no.
这是标准通用的
This is all the standard space, so basically any browser
基本上所有浏览器都能从 link rel 标签中
can look for this link rel tag that links to your manifest
链接到你的 manifest JSON 文件  解析它
JSON file, at that point they can parse it
你想要实现的那些
and it's just going to-- you have certain things
浏览器就会展现出来
to find for then browsers to take it all out.
好
ADDY OSMANI: Right.
所以说 manifest 能让我修改图标
So the manifest lets me customize my icons.
还有其他什么是我能配置的么
What other stuff can I configure in there?
你可以定义 short name
MATT GAUNT: So, you can define short name, which
它会显示在你常使用的图标下
would be the text underneath your icon that you'd normally see.
Theme color  Chrome 会在 URL 栏
Theme color, which Chrome uses, is like the URL color
给 URL 设定颜色
along the URL bar.
Background color  在启动画面中使用
Background color is for the splash screen.
如果你已经添加到主屏幕  点击后
So, if you have that add to home screen, then click on it,
它就会启动  基本上当 Chrome 在加载时
it'll launch and basically while Chrome's loading, what
你可以展示以单色为底
you can do is show a splash screen that's
包括带有文字的图标
like a solid color and then have an icon on top of it
的启动画面
along with the text.
这就是 Background color 的用处
So background color does that.
比如你有一系列的图标
You've got an array of icons, so again,
它会根据浏览器需要使用图标的场景
depending on what the browser want's to use the icon for,
选择大小最合适的
it will just pick the best size for it.
Start URL 非常棒
Start URL is super awesome.
它的用处是
What that is, is basically-- you remember back
你还记得原来我们在 Chrome 中使用添加到主屏幕么
in the day we used to have add to home screen in Chrome?
它藏在菜单中
It was like hidden in the menu.
恩
ADDY OSMANI: Yeah.
它的作用就是
MATT GAUNT: So, what that would always do
不管你在哪个页面
is whatever page you're on that is where you will get
当你点击添加到主屏幕时  都会重新指向它
pointed when you click on the icon for the home screen.
Start URL 可以设定它在哪
Start URL let's you define where that is now.
比如有人正在看博客文章
So, if someone was in the middle of a blog article, clicked
点击添加到主屏幕  现在你就知道了
on add to home screen, now you can say, actually, just
它会回到博客主页
go to the home of the blog.
你还可以配置 display
Then you've got display.
display 不是以浏览器模式启动
Display is basically rather than launch in browser mode,
它可以全屏显示
you can say actually I want it to go full screen.
它就像原生应用一样
ADDY OSMANI: Oh, so you can launch it full
能够全屏显示  是么
screen the same way that a native app might look like, right?
就是这样
MATT GAUNT: Yeah, exactly.
除此之外  还有 orientations
But, alongside that there is, also, in the spec, orientations.
理论上你可以锁定为纵向或者横向
So you could theoretically lock it to portrait or landscape.
棒  这对游戏很有用
ADDY OSMANI: Oh, cool, so for games that's particularly useful.
对  当你想只用手柄时
MATT GAUNT: Yeah, if you want to do like forced-- thumb sticks.
关于 start URL
The nice thing, especially, I was
还有一点特别棒
going to say with the Start URL, you can actually then add
你可以添加查询参数
the query parameter, so then you can track
这样你就能追踪到使用人数了
how many people are using it.
啊
ADDY OSMANI: Ah.
比如主屏幕参数为真值
MATT GAUNT: So, like home screen equals true.
分析结果就会显示给你
And then analytics would just show you.
不错
ADDY OSMANI: Cool.
基本上就是这些东西了
MATT GAUNT: So that's pretty much the bulk of it.
好的
ADDY OSMANI: Nice.
有没有  比如我想验证 manifest 的合法性
Is there-- if I wanted to like validate
有没有什么工具可以做到这一点
that I've got a legit manifest, is there are tool I can use for that?
有  有人做了一个 web app manifest 验证器
MATT GAUNT: Yes, someone has built a web app manifest validator.
我觉得 DevTools 也会实现这个功能
I think DevTools were also going to do it
你可以下载 manifest
so you can like force a download the manifest
让 DevTools 去解析它
and get DevTools to parse it.
我觉得我们在 Totally Tooling Tears 中也提到过
ADDY OSMANI: I believe we mentioned as much in Totally Tooling Tears.
但我还没亲自用过
MATT GAUNT: But I haven't actually used it yet, myself.
诚然  如果你不用这类工具
And, admittedly, if you don't use something like that,
就很难知道 manifest 有没有效
it's kind of hard to figure out whether it's working or not.
所以值得去验证一下
So those are well worth checking out.
好吧  所以我们谈到了 web app manifest
ADDY OSMANI: OK, so we talked about the web app
还有用来验证它的 manifest 验证器
manifest, the manifest validator, for checking out,
DevTools 也在着手这个
DevTools is looking at it.
有没有这方面的文档可以参考呢
Are there docs on this available as well?
最佳的参考资料就是我们的博客文章
MATT GAUNT: The best thing to look at is [INAUDIBLE] blog post.
它包括示例 manifests  如何把它加到 HTML 页面
It covers example manifests, how do I get it to the HTML page,
还有如何调试它
and then how to debug it as well.
这应该是最好的方法了
So that's probably the best bet.
真棒
ADDY OSMANI: Sweet.
还有它包括在 web starter kit 里
MATT GAUNT: And plus it's in web starter kit,
以及我们做的很多其他项目中
and a whole other host of the projects that we do.
[MUSIC PLAYING]